

Khalid Moro

Looking for a job as a Software engineer / Data engineer

□ +33753987613 **♀** 62 Rue Edouard Vaillant 93100 Montreuil France

□ morokhalid16@gmail.com

(in)

LinkedIn



Github



I am an enthusiast data engineer with a strong skill set. I possess qualities such as self-motivation, high energy, attention to detail, and effective communication skills. I am a lifelong learner who relishes new challenges and opportunities to expand my knowledge and expertise

Experiences

Data Engineer P&L Explanation

NATIXIS BEYOND BANKING

Natixis - Since January 2023

- ▶ Design, implementation, and monitoring of new features for our spark application
- Provide support to resolve production issues
- Automate data processing jobs via control M
- Use CI/CD best practices and code monitoring with SonarQube

Data Engineer / Software Engineer



SSP - January 2022 to December 2022

- ▶ Built data pipelines with Python and Sql then automated with Bash and Airflow
- Applied data analysis techniques to define key performance indicators and decrease the risk of non-payment through the use of Tableau software
- Designed and created fraud detection models for accurately scoring transactions
- Automated deployment process with the use of Docker and Jenkins technologies

Data Scientist



Société Générale - May 2021 to November 2021

- Compiled a bibliography on the topic of algorithmic equity
- Developed an equity tracking tool utilizing recent techniques
- Integrated the solution with a focus on utilizing best practices in software engineering (Git, Jira, Jenkins)

Data Engineer

Crédit Mutuel ARKEA

Crédit Mutuel Arkéa - May 2020 to September 2020

- Design and upgrade pipelines for the extraction and transformation of financial, extra-financial and regulatory data from Crédit Mutuel Arkéa's partner asset management companies
- ▶ End-to-end automation of several manual tasks: reports, statistical studies
- > Documentation and communication of all the obtained results

Python Developer

WEELITE - February 2019 to March 2019

- Collecting and analyzing customer needs: designing an electronic archiving solution
- ▶ Implementation of the solution as a Flask API
- Unit testing and solution deployment

Communications Manager

Atlantique Sans Frontières - September 2018 to August 2020

- Played a role as part of the organizational team for a humanitarian trip to Ivory Coast.
- ▶ Communication tools management: social networks, LinkedIn
- Planning and running meetings

Education

Engineering Degree (Master's Degree)

IMT Atlantique (ex Télécom Bretagne)

September 2018 to September 2021

- School accessible through the French Mines-Ponts competitions.
- Double curriculum: Data science and digital platforms

Admission to the Grandes Ecoles

CPGE Reda Slaoui, Agadir, Morocco

September 2015 to September 2017

Intensive courses in Mathematics, Physics and Engineering Sciences

Skills

Soft Skills

- Project management
- Agility (Tool: JIRA Software)

Technical skills

Python, Scala, Java, C++ Bash scripting, Airflow, Control M, SQL, Tableau,

Power BI, Jenkins, XL

Release / Deploy,

Machine Learning/Deep learning

Spark, Kafka, Docker,

Hadoop, Hive

Cloud: AWS, IBM, GCP

Languages

English (Fluent): IELTS 8/9 French (bilingual)

Arabic (bilingual)